I have been using this policy since the beginning of the year.
I took it in December 2019.
10 lakhs policy.
I have been using this policy since then.
Why am I making a video about the policy you are using?
I told you in the last video.
You know how to select a good policy,
what you should see and what you shouldn't.
But if you go ahead and buy it, you will see 100 plans.
If you try to apply the theory you learned in those 100 plans,
you will be facing a lot of questions.
Why am I using this policy?
Our team members are there to present you videos.
Why did they use this 10 lakhs policy and not this 1 crore policy?
What policy should I take for my family?
I will show you companies in this video.
The policy we are talking about is related to health insurance.
If you don't want to see this,
you can have 5 lakhs or 10 lakhs hospital bills in your bank account.
You can have 20 lakhs in your bank account.
You don't need to see this video if you don't want to see the impact of those 20 lakhs.
Because a hospital bill can save a middle class person for 10-20 years.
I am not saying this to make a video.
I am not taking this policy for making a video.
I am taking this policy since 2015.
I am taking this policy before talking about this.
I am doing this for my family and I will do the same for you and your family.
I am explaining to you in detail what I took for you.
I am explaining to you in detail to a 5th class student.
Keep taking and not taking aside.
Watch this video till the end.
So that you can give a good policy to your family members and your friends.
Before we start the video, I am telling you again.
There are many videos in our channel.
There are many concepts like health insurance in YouTube and internet.
But practically, there are no policies to review.
But the industry standards are to take the latest data from IRD and bring it to the front.
Do you think our efforts are valuable?
Like this video.
Because this is a theoretical video.
I can work for a day or two.
But this video is working for weeks.
I need your support 100%.
Like this video.
You watch this video.
If we share this video, you will find it useful for them too.
Share this video.
I won't tell you what to check and compare while taking health insurance.
Because I will talk about policies.
I will explain in simple language.
But before taking insurance, I will answer the questions that a person might have.
After that, whoever you go to take insurance, they will check everything and stop at these 3 insurance companies.
If we take the top 3, it is HDFC, Argo, K and Neva Bupa.
I will compare these 3 in today's video.
Those who are already in the health insurance field, they will select these 3 options in the meantime.
They will stop at the options they want to take.
I will compare these 3.
You will understand how to look at the remaining options.
After talking about the insurance that suits each individual,
you will take health insurance.
But ultimately, when you are climbing, you shouldn't get into trouble.
There are some facts that you shouldn't neglect.
I will briefly explain the important things that you should check while taking insurance.
I will give you the details of the policy that I take.
Because I am going to take it now and change the policy.
I will explain why I am taking it and why I am changing it and end this video.
First question. Why do I need health insurance?
If I need it, I will pay Rs.500 and go to the hospital.
They will give me small tablets and I will come back.
Friends, I used to think like that till a point of time.
But when I think about it, in my family, even in the families I know,
autoimmune diseases like,
we don't get any infection, we don't get any mosquitoes, we don't get any accidents, nothing like that.
Our internal body, our immune system attacks our body parts.
We don't get autoimmune diseases.
Due to lack of proper quality foods, pesticides, chemicals,
wherever we are, the air quality is getting affected.
Even in water, the chemicals that we don't know are coming into our body day to day.
At what point, what disease, particularly autoimmune and cancer related diseases,
I know how much it cost me.
When my grandma got cancer, I know how much we spent.
When I saw that, in the hospitals,
when I saw people who were treating with health insurance card without paying a single rupee,
I decided to take health insurance after I finished my studies and started getting money.
After I started getting money, I took health insurance in my house first,
then I convinced my family members to take health insurance too.
So, in any house, when something happens to their wife or child,
if they can pay 5, 10, 20 lakhs on average,
there won't be any problem in their house.
They will have that money in their bank account.
Or, if they can spend that money, they don't need health insurance.
Why do they need health insurance for Aadhaani and Ambani?
Why do they spend that time? They don't need health insurance.
But, the money that you are saving, the money that you are saving for your children,
the money that you are saving for your savings,
a small hospital bill, a small event,
it will have a mental impact.
But, if we are talking about a hospital bill that is 5, 10 years behind us,
then we definitely need to take health insurance.
I am telling you again, if I want to make a video,
don't think that I am getting paid by some companies.
If you are giving money, you should talk about one company.
Let's say, two companies give money together.
I will talk about 3-4 companies now.
In which video, the people who take money and promote you,
won't talk about so many companies.
They will talk about one company only.
So, this is not a video that I am making for myself.
Watch it only for the sake of our family members.
So, I told you who should take health insurance, right?
Second, I am getting health insurance from a company.
Or, from the government's health insurance or from some schemes.
I have health insurance. Should I also take health insurance?
I should.
The health insurance that the company gives you,
you, your children, your family members,
like your mother and father,
may have been given with some limits.
First, see how much health insurance your company gives.
Let's say, if it gives 2 lakhs,
if it is a problem and it is a 5 lakhs bill,
if it is a 10 lakhs bill,
you should give the remaining 7-8 lakhs, right?
In the current hospital bills,
if you are undergoing an important surgery in a medium-level hospital,
or if it is an accident-related complication,
in a scenario that costs up to 10 lakhs,
how much health insurance will your company give you?
If it is a health insurance or some schemes from the government,
they won't pay the entire bill.
There will be limits to it.
When the treatment is costing,
if you want to put certain medical instruments in your body,
they will put a limit to it.
They will say that they won't pay beyond this.
To avoid those problems,
first, check the limits of your insurance,
whether it is from the company or the government.
If there are very few limits,
they should definitely take health insurance.
If it is a 10-20 lakhs bill,
the health insurance that comes from them will save us.
Most of the insurance may be yours,
and may not be available to your family.
So, you should take a good policy for the entire family's health.
It is your responsibility as the person earning it.
And third, I told you to take it, right?
Don't take a policy for you, your children, your parents, your wife, and everyone.
Take a policy for you, your wife, your children, and your parents.
Because they are old and have some kind of disease,
your premium will increase because of them.
And fourth,
after taking health insurance,
I will explain the details to you.
If you want to change something,
or if you want to go into this because you have this advantage,
you can change it.
But you can't stop it and change it.
You can port it into this.
There is a portability feature.
I am already paying for a health insurance.
I want to take another health insurance.
This is another company.
I will tell you the advantages of porting it.
I will explain why I am porting the company I am presenting in the ending.
I will explain each of these three companies individually.
Before explaining,
I will open the website in front of you.
You will see many terms in it.
What is this? What is that?
We should explain this clearly, right?
We should explain these terms, right?
There are many videos related to this in our channel.
I have already explained multiple times.
It is not right to explain it again, right?
I want to explain this practically.
So, theoretically, you need complete knowledge about health insurance.
If you want to know everything,
you can watch these videos in the description section.
Watch it in your free time.
You will have total knowledge.
But now I want to talk practically.
Friends, when you want to take health insurance,
they ask you for details.
For example, in the description section,
there is a link to how to take a good health insurance.
Policy Bazaar link.
Click on it.
They will ask you for details if you click on it.
Fill out the details exactly.
Do not lie.
If you have a problem or any health problem,
tell them everything.
Because some health insurance companies ask for insurance for some problems.
Some increase it.
Tell them exactly what you have.
Because it is not important to take it.
You can take an insurance by lying.
But when you are claiming,
you should not tell them that you lied to me.
Fill out the details exactly.
You will get all these plans.
In the starting,
Care, Neva Bhoopa, Star, Aditya Billa, HDFC,
ICE, Reliance, Bajaj Alliance, Manipal Sikna,
Tata AIG, New and A Assurance, Royal Sundaram,
SBI, Chola, multiple health insurance companies.
I told you that this is a paid video.
I want to talk about only one company.
I should not mention another competitor in the video.
So, in all these insurance companies,
I told you about the companies.
In Care, there are 9 plans.
Neva Bhoopa has 11 plans.
Star has 6 plans.
Aditya Billa has 10 plans.
I have an ocean of health insurance.
We can talk about term insurance.
But health insurance is like an ocean of plans.
Time to time, time to time,
there are many changes happening.
So, I will take three things from this.
Why did I take three?
HDFC, Care and Neva Bhoopa.
Please watch the screen.
With respect to business,
HDFC is top.
Care is in second place.
The main reason for selecting Neva Bhoopa is their features.
If you see,
the rest is waste.
This is the best.
But there is a different point in it.
There is a different aspect.
Let's talk about that too.
So, if you see the videos theoretically,
and come to take health insurance,
and compare everything,
you will stop at these three things.
That's why I will tell you these three things.
The third is, the main reason to keep Neva Bhoopa.
Our team members also see the videos,
knowledge related, everything.
Their own plans went to Neva Bhoopa.
I understand why they had to go there.
But personally, I don't suggest that.
I won't say that you should take Neva Bhoopa as well.
Why?
There are many aspects in this.
I will tell you one by one, simply for 5th class students.
Please watch carefully.
First, I am going to tell you about HDFC Ergo.
There are two popular plans related to HDFC Ergo.
One is Optima Securing and the other is Optima Restore.
Before talking about the plans,
let's talk about the history of insurance.
HDFC Ergo is a joint venture.
It was formed by two organizations.
HDFC is related to India.
Ergo is a insurance company related to Germany.
In 2002, they both founded HDFC Ergo.
But they weren't good in the health insurance segment.
They were small players.
So, they believed in policies.
But in 2020, they won 51% in Apollo Munich.
This is a turnaround step.
They won 51% and the majority of the games.
They grew as a strong insurance player.
They are the leader in the health insurance segment with 9.7% market share.
The next two companies are standalone health insurance companies.
But this is a general insurance company.
What is the difference between them?
General insurance company is not just about health insurance.
In the name of HDFC Ergo,
health insurance is one segment.
There are other segments like motor insurance,
two-wheeler, four-wheeler insurance,
car and bike insurance,
home insurance.
So, all these are combined to form a general insurance company.
In the stand alone, it provides only health insurance.
The reason I am telling this clearly is,
general insurance, like HDFC Ergo,
doesn't focus on health insurance.
So, there might not be any specific plans.
But those who focus on health insurance,
they might provide plans and riders as we want.
Like a buffet, they might provide as we want.
But they are not like that.
They will tell you meals if you go to a hotel.
They will give you a set as standard.
HDFC Ergo will give you that.
Now, let's compare the important things.
Please observe this carefully.
Because, I will be talking about the policy I am going to take
in this company's policy.
If you observe here,
the claim settlement ratio is high in the industry.
98% for HDFC Ergo.
91% for Care and 91% for Neva Bupa.
Claim settlement ratio means,
if they have 100 claims,
we joined the hospital.
If they have 100 claims,
how many claims they are settling,
how much more it is, is good.
Here, you are not seeing the last year's.
I mean, not last year's.
Not 2023.
2023, 2022, 2021.
These are the average of 3 years.
Because, in a year, someone might be the best.
In the remaining years, someone might be the worst.
So, I took the average of 3 years.
So, with respect to claim settlement ratio,
HDFC is top.
Second is incurred claim ratio.
If you observe here,
HDFC Ergo has 85%,
Care has 58% and Neva Bupa has 57%.
So, Care and Neva Bupa are similar.
Whereas, HDFC Ergo has 85%.
Incurred claim ratio means,
I am a insurance company.
I am collecting premiums at 100 crores.
In the name of health insurance.
I am collecting money from you all at 100 crores.
How much I am spending from these 100 crores.
I mean, when I need people to take health insurance policy,
how much percent I am spending from these 100 crores,
that is incurred claim ratio.
If Care is collecting 100 rupees or 100 crores,
So, how much more I spend is better?
We don't need to see that.
Because, some companies are above 100.
So, they are collecting more than they are paying.
They are going to risk.
So, usually, it is better to see this number at 75-80.
But, HDFC Ergo is a standard brand.
So, the amount they get,
the majority of the things they get,
they are spending for claims.
We can take it positively.
Network hospitals are similar here.
All are near 9000 or above.
So, there is no big differentiation here.
This is important.
Complaints.
If we go to 10,000 claims,
they are not paying hospital bill,
but 10,000 claims.
Not policies.
If we go to 10,000 claims,
out of 10,000 claims,
how many customers are facing problems?
This is important.
I will tell you what policies you should take next.
The main reason for HDFC Ergo to be less is,
they are not a standalone health insurance company.
Not only health insurance,
they have general insurance too.
Motor, home,
they sell those insurances too.
When you see that,
when you see how many claims they are getting,
how many rejections they are giving to customers,
probably, HDFC Ergo is less for that.
It can be a benefit.
But, when you see overall,
with respect to data, pure data,
HDFC Ergo is at the top.
Now, let's compare their policies.
Optima Secure and Optima Restore.
I am comparing both.
Compare now.
Friends, until a long time ago,
Optima Restore was actually from Apollo Munich.
After they took it,
it changed to HDFC Ergo Optima Restore.
But, after they took Apollo Munich,
we took it in 2020,
the superb plan they brought then was Optima Secure.
Compare this to this.
There is no big difference in premiums.
But, if you compare this to this,
the cover here is 5 lakhs.
They are asking you to pay this much for 5 lakhs.
But, if you take Optima Secure,
from the first day,
they will give you 5 lakhs for the cover.
So, the money you are paying is 5 lakhs.
If you take Restore,
the money you are paying is 5 lakhs.
But, if you take Secure,
pay the same amount for 5 lakhs.
They are saying they will give you another 5 lakhs for additional.
So, there is no logic in taking Restore.
You should definitely take Optima Secure.
There is no logic in taking Restore.
So, if you want to take any plan in HDFC Ergo,
I will definitely take Optima Secure.
I have told you about the comparisons.
There are many videos in which there are bold things.
Like, there should be no anger,
no room rent limit,
or there should be no disease related sub-limits.
You should cover the expenses of pre and post hospitalization.
You should cover the ambulance charges.
You should cover the day care treatments.
Like, you should not join the hospital.
You should cover the small treatments in a day.
I have told you all these things.
Check these and these are good.
All these are there in this.
There is nothing to check in that.
There is nothing to say that this is negative or not.
Everything is covered in this.
Even the basic things are covered in this.
Is everything positive?
Let's go to the negatives.
As I told you, this is a general insurance company.
They couldn't give their insurance to specific problems.
They are bringing some new policies in recent times.
Even now, compared to Care Mall,
compared to other standalone health insurance companies,
they are not giving a good policy for aged people.
And they are not giving it to those who have health related problems.
I will explain this to you simply.
I have set the age to 21.
If I set it to 21, I will get HDFC Ergo.
If I set it to 66,
if I set it to 66,
HDFC Ergo will not come.
Care will come, Niva will come.
Everything else will come but HDFC Ergo will not come.
So, those who are planning to take it for their parents,
this is not suitable for them.
And those who have a specific illness,
like BP, Diabetes or any other problems,
and they are planning to cover it for 30 days,
this is not suitable for them.
There are many riders in this.
To add some advantages,
to add some changes,
this is also not suitable.
There is no maternity cover in this.
There is no cover for pregnant women to cover their children's birth related problems.
So, all these are negative related.
For whom?
For those who are young and fit and fine,
and who don't have any health related problems,
they are paying a little more.
If we compare it with other health insurance companies,
they charge more money.
Why do they charge?
Because of HDFC brand,
because of their numbers,
the claim settlement ratio is top,
and they are claiming more money.
I have searched for the reviews on Twitter and online,
I have searched for the reasons and how to stop the claims.
I understood everything.
Compared with other insurance companies,
they are passing the claims very easily.
I found complaints about 1 or 2 companies.
But compared with other companies,
even if we have complaints with pregnant women,
they have very few complaints.
If we have complaints with other companies,
we can get the claim smoothly.
If we have any requirement on that day,
we can get the claim,
whether it is cashless or in the past,
this seemed very smooth.
I have confidence that I will get the claim without any headache.
I have understood this research with my own analysis that HDFC is with Ergo.
Next, I will shift to this insurance.
Because I am young and healthy,
I don't have any present problems.
So, I will take this.
If in case, my age has increased a bit,
let's say I am 35 or 40 years old,
if I have diabetes, hypertension,
or any health related problems,
or if I have to take health insurance for my parents for 65 years,
I will keep this aside completely.
Even if I am aged,
I will not take it even if they give me.
I will go to care.
Now, let's talk about the care insurance that we have put in second preference.
This was under ReliGear insurance.
They started it in 2012.
But in 2020, they changed the name to Care insurance.
This is standalone insurance.
They only have health insurance.
And this Climb Settlement Ratio,
In-Curve Climb Ratio,
how many network hospitals are there,
and how many complaints are there on them,
all these will be on the screen.
We have explained it previously.
There is no need to discuss it again.
If we compare all these data,
after HDFC, Ergo, they will be in second place.
That's why we are discussing this.
And if we talk about insurance related to them,
you will see a lot of plans.
In that, I personally take the Care Supreme Direct plan.
Before taking this,
you will see a guaranteed 7X return.
I have to explain about that.
What they are saying is,
how you are paying premium money for the starting 5 lakhs in Optima Secure,
and how you will get the benefit from the first 5 lakhs,
here, the insurance cover you are taking,
they say they will increase it to 600% in the next 5 years.
Even if you take the Climb,
this is not about No Climb bonus.
It is not about increasing the Climb if we don't do anything.
Even if you do the Climb,
even if you take the hospital bill from 1000,
or if you don't take it,
time to time,
the health insurance cover you are taking will increase,
and after 5 years,
if you take the first 5 lakhs,
after 5 years,
it will increase by 600%.
5X6 is 30 lakhs.
Plus, you took 5 lakhs.
Totally, it will be 35 lakhs.
But the money you are paying is for those 5 lakhs.
They have clearly mentioned it here.
It will increase by 600% in 5 years,
even if you climb.
This is the important feature related to this.
Apart from this,
whatever benefits we talked about earlier,
we should check all these theoretically.
Will there be a room rent limit?
Or will there be sub-limits?
Will there be anger?
Pre and post hospitalization expense.
All these will be included in this.
You will get a positive output.
If you check all these theoretically,
you won't have any red flags.
Oh, this is there, right?
I will not leave this.
Then what are the red flags,
the negatives?
To avoid this.
Before talking about that, let's talk about the positives.
This is a standalone health insurance company.
They provide a lot of riders and add-ons.
This will be very beneficial.
As I told you earlier,
if I have any health related problems,
I will take this.
Why I will take this is,
the riders who are getting this,
there is an instant cover.
If I add this,
my health insurance will get another 1370 rupees.
yearly.
See the benefit I get because of that.
If I have diabetes,
or BP,
or hyperlipidemia,
or asthma,
or any of these problems,
if I join the hospital after 30 days,
they will give me my complete money.
Or else,
there is a waiting period of 4 years.
You should understand this carefully.
Let's say, I told them I have hypertension.
Due to hypertension,
if I have any problem,
let's say, I have a heart problem due to hypertension,
or any other heart problem,
they won't give money for that.
Usually, they won't give money.
What will they say?
You already have hypertension,
so, because of that, you have this problem.
Wait for 3 years.
They will say they will cover it for 3 years.
But, I am adding this now,
there is no need to wait for 3 years.
Actually, they have a waiting period of 4 years.
All the remaining 3 years are there.
They have 4 years.
If I don't add this,
I have to wait for 4 years.
Instead of waiting for 4 years,
I have to wait for the remaining 3 years for 30 days.
This is 30 days.
If anyone has diabetes or hypertension,
due to that, there are many complications.
Diabetes has complications.
Hypertension has complications.
For that, waiting period is 30 days.
From then, we can easily take this card,
health insurance card,
and get any treatment done in the hospital for free.
Next, pre-existing diseases.
I told you that there is a waiting period of 4 years.
If I have to reduce it to 3 years,
or if I can wait for 2 years,
or if I have to reduce it to 1 year,
if I pay for it,
I have to wait for the remaining 3 years for all the remaining companies.
But, if I pay this much money,
I can reduce my waiting period to 1 year,
for any existing problem.
This benefit won't be there for many companies.
So, in HDFC compared with CARE,
annual health check-up is available for us in Optima Secure.
It comes with the base plan.
Claim Shield too.
I mean, there are consumables.
Whatever the surgery is done,
the treatment cost, doctor's cost is the main.
Along with that, the gloves they wear,
the syringes they use,
small equipments,
all these are a bit costly.
For 2-7 persons,
the total cost of the consumables is there.
Here, you can cover it by adding Claim Shield.
You don't have to add anything in HDFC Secure.
In fact, you don't have to add anything like this.
But, it is covered automatically.
So, compared to CARE, the premium is more.
But, if we add these too,
it is a bit comparable.
Still, it is still more premium.
We have to pay more for HDFC and other things.
We can pay according to convenience and brand.
Or, I can reduce the amount.
And, I can reduce the waiting period
for my health problems and my parents' health problems.
If I want to use the health insurance card as soon as possible,
CARE is the best option that we have.
So, these are the advantages of this.
Another advantage is that,
even if you are 90 years old,
they will give you insurance policy.
Many other companies won't give you insurance policy.
So, if you want to take it for your parents who are older,
you can take it in CARE.
And, I want to reduce the time period
by telling them about the conditions.
If they want to pay the insurance policy
in the hospital within the next 30 days,
this is the best option for you.
If we talk about negatives,
if we compare it with HDFC Ergo,
and why we should take HDFC Ergo,
and compare it with this,
we should say negatives, right?
If we think like that, HDFC Ergo is smooth.
They don't drill us much.
They don't ask why this and that.
Complaints are easy to get.
But, if we compare it with this,
I'm not saying it's worst.
Because, no insurance company is the best.
But, comparatively,
there are some questions in the situation.
In 100, 99% of the people might face such a situation.
But, there are chances to ask more questions when faced with it.
Because of their complaints.
And, waiting period.
In the normal base plan,
everyone else gives 3 years.
But, they would have given 4 years.
They would have given it as riders to reduce it.
And, there is no annual health check up.
Consumables are not in the base plan.
So, I see it as negatives.
But, if I had to take it,
I would have taken it as well.
If I have any problem and I have to reduce the waiting period,
this is the option I have.
In the 3 insurance companies we talked about earlier.
Final insurance company, Neva Bupa.
They started this in 2010 as Max Bupa.
Max people related to India.
Bupa people related to UK.
How HDFC and Ergo got together.
They also started Max Bupa insurance in 2010.
But, in 2021,
Max people, Max India people exited.
They bought their entire stake, their water,
True North people.
And, from 2021, they brought Neva Bupa.
Is this a general insurance company or a standalone health insurance company?
Standalone.
They sell only health insurance.
And, their client settlement ratio, incurred client ratio,
how many complaints they have,
their network hospitals,
all these are on the screen.
Compared with HDFC and Ergo and Care,
they are in 3rd place.
Particularly, their complaints are a little heavy.
If you see my reviews,
the features are amazing.
When you see those features,
it looks very attractive.
Complaints are a little heavy.
Compared with other two,
they ask a little more details.
If you send them a document to claim in the hospital,
or if you try to go to the cashless,
whatever data you fill with them,
they want to keep it close to their body.
They should have it like that.
Keep it close to their body,
and every data they give should be true.
Whatever mistakes you make,
whatever small clue you give,
you should face the issues next.
So, without any issue,
you should give them all the data correctly,
and even the issues related to the doctor,
if they ask you 3 questions,
you can follow up.
I'm a little young, I have the knowledge,
I'll make sure everything is correct,
I can pass the claim.
If you have a strong mindset,
it's better to take this.
If you compare it with those two,
because, with respect to money,
in Bronze plus Reissue 2.0,
you'll get all the benefits you need.
There are advantages too,
I'll tell you the advantages.
Along with the advantages,
if you compare it with the benefits you get,
you'll get even better benefits,
at a lower price.
You'll get everything you need here.
You'll get all the advantages,
no matter where you look at it,
you'll get it for less money.
But, you can handle it properly.
If they ask you something,
you can deal with it.
If we don't have any mistakes,
no one can do anything.
They won't try to force us to come.
But, if you can handle the issue,
if you can handle the issue,
then this will be the best for you.
The main benefit in this is,
I'll tell you a plan,
you'll see a lot of plans here,
Gold plus, Bronze, bold plans,
I'm one of them.
If we consider this as the base,
Reissue 2.0 Bronze plus,
next is Titanium,
next is Platinum.
If you want to invest more,
you can go for those plans.
There's only one benefit in those three.
There won't be a big difference,
but some features will be better than this.
I'm taking the base plan.
I told you that features will make you go crazy.
Unlimited Restoration Cover Forever.
How many times do you use that insurance?
It's getting restored every time.
Not just once,
it's getting restored every time.
Since this is Bronze,
they'll increase it three times.
We're taking Summashree.
If they increase it three times,
you'll get 10 lakhs policy.
In the next three years,
your base plan will be 10 lakhs.
It'll be 40 lakhs in total.
You'll pay 10 lakhs.
If you take Platinum,
it'll be five times in Platinum.
In the next five years,
you'll get 50 lakhs in addition.
You'll get 10 lakhs.
It'll be 60 lakhs in total.
You'll pay 10 lakhs.
If you take Titanium,
it'll be 10 times.
If you keep paying that insurance for the next 10 years,
you'll get 1 crore in addition.
You'll get 1.1 crore for the base plan.
Even if you claim it,
it'll be worth it.
It's not like you can't get it in hospitals.
In simple terms,
time to time,
the money you're paying will be the same.
But time to time,
your cover will increase.
Even if you claim it.
Disease management.
If you have diabetes or hypertension,
it'll start getting covered from day one.
You'll have to pay extra for it.
But I'm telling you,
we don't have an add-on rider like this in HDFC.
We'll add this to our policy
to see if it gets covered immediately.
So, to cover disease management,
hypertension and diabetes will be covered from day one.
So, people with more problems will get more care.
They'll provide more care.
Care insurances.
Not your parents.
Care.
If you're a cancer patient,
or if you have rheumatoid arthritis,
or if you have any critical illness,
they'll give you insurance.
The rest will think about giving you.
But here,
you'll get a benefit related to hypertension and diabetes.
They'll get it from day one.
So, who should take this?
Finally,
we have a tight budget.
I can't pay more.
I'll spend less money
for health insurance starting days.
But if anything happens,
I'll take care of everything that's around me.
I can talk to the health insurance company.
What if they don't give us money?
I'll tell you at the end.
If we try to cheat the insurance company,
we'll have to get money with interest.
But we have a tight budget.
I'm saving money here.
So, I'll put in extra effort.
It's not like 100 out of 100 cases.
It's like 10 out of 10 cases.
So, if I can put in extra effort,
they'll get good features with less money.
So, that's number three.
Finally,
I'll put in extra premium.
I don't have any problems.
I'll take the base plan and get good benefits.
If I get a smooth claim,
HDFC is optimal and secure.
Not a restore.
Second,
Care Supreme Plan.
They'll have add-ons and writers to our problems.
They'll add them.
We can get the benefits with less decisions.
That's what I was talking about.
Neva Bhupa.
I have a tight budget.
I need to save money and get the best benefits.
But I face some problems in the claim process.
I explained that it suits some people.
Now,
you can click the link in the description and fill the details.
Someone will call you while you're watching.
You can ask the person you're calling,
and they'll fix the policy you're going to take.
We don't need any advantages.
Keep it aside.
We can see it clearly with big headings.
I don't want to cover in this policy.
You should ask for negatives first.
Don't ask for positives or negatives.
We'll decide whether to take it or not.
Those who called us,
will try to say something that we don't want.
Ask for negatives.
And tell them about your diseases clearly.
Tell them that you don't want it.
Tell them to mention everything you take out.
You'll either give it or take it from others.
If they don't claim it, it'll be a loss.
Tell them everything.
Check whether the hospital you're going to is in the network hospital.
How to check?
Get a plan,
view all features,
come to cashless hospitals.
There are 61 cashless hospitals in Visakhapatnam.
Search for the name and check whether the hospital is there.
Before going to the hospital,
inform your insurance company.
Or inform them after joining.
Because,
even if you try to get refund after getting treated,
insurance companies will put obstacles.
They'll think you're faking it.
Inform them before going.
Or inform them after joining.
Finally, if you want to buy insurance,
store every document of your future treatments.
If they give annual health checkups,
get them done for free.
So that you both have proof.
So that you don't have the disease at that point.
And if it comes in future,
you don't have to hide it.
Whatever you tell the insurance company,
you should tell the doctor.
It should reflect in your treatment.
Wherever it gets mismatched,
you should give the insurance company a chance.
Keep that in mind.
If you lie and take insurance,
you'll waste all the money you paid for the insurance.
Be honest and tell the truth till you know it.
If there's an issue,
be an agent to talk on your behalf.
Because,
you've shifted from one place to another.
You're not in contact with the agent.
You're not able to change the climate.
You face issues.
Be a strong agent.
If you take support from online platforms,
they'll provide support to you.
Policy bazaar people provide 30 minutes of support.
If you're in a hospital or facing an issue,
they'll provide support to you.
If you call them and inform them,
they'll sort out your issues within 30 minutes.
They'll provide 30 minutes of support.
If you're facing any issues,
you need someone to talk to.
Don't take health insurance directly from an insurance company.
Because,
if you face any issues,
the insurance company won't talk on your behalf.
Either take it from an agent,
or from an aggregator website.
A website that compares insurance.
Whether you take it directly from an agent,
aggregator or anyone else,
there's only one premium.
No one should give you a discount.
Everyone takes the same amount.
If you take it directly from an insurance company,
if you want to talk to them,
they won't help you.
That health insurance company,
when they need to give you money,
will they fight for you or them?
So, you need an agent to fight for you.
Or an aggregator online.
Policy bazaar people say,
if you have an issue with us,
we'll support you in 30 minutes.
A person related to them,
a hospital you're in,
will help you get through the insurance claim.
They'll send you from there.
They'll support you.
You can take it from any aggregator,
or from an insurance agent.
But, I personally buy it online.
I was in Chittoor at first.
If I bought it from an agent,
I moved to Nellore.
I'm in Vizag now.
I can go to another place.
Or, if my agent left the health insurance business,
and quit the business,
or if I'm doing something,
what can I ask them?
I took insurance from you.
I can't pressure them.
So, if you compare yourself with an aggregator online,
will they support you in the claim?
If you have an issue, will they fight for you?
Take it from an agent.
He'll be in the same business.
He'll sell health insurance.
He'll fight for me.
He'll take care of me.
He's been doing it for a long time.
If you believe me,
take it from an offline agent.
Take it from your favorite.
I took it online.
Because, no matter where I am,
I need their support.
They'll help me in the 30 minutes of their support.
In the worst case,
in 100s,
there are fewer cases than this.
If we get a time when all the doors are closed,
and no one cares about us,
that won't happen.
I haven't got any clients till now.
Not many, but if anyone comes to me,
and if they don't know about their claim,
or if they don't know anything,
and if they don't want to give me the claim,
then watch this video.
If a health insurance company says,
they won't give you the claim,
they simply fill the data online,
and give you some documents.
How did you get the money from the bank account?
Our subscriber,
who follows our channel,
will tell you the process of getting the money.
I've also told you about the process of IRDA.
The insurance related regulatory authority.
I've explained how you can complain about the money.
Everyone will give you the complete knowledge.
Everything will be beautiful when you take it.
But, when there's an issue,
all the doors will be closed.
So, watch this video before that.
Feed the knowledge in your mind.
And, do this.
Because, you might not remember what I said.
You might not remember the video.
The link is in the description.
Before closing,
if you're not taking health insurance for yourself,
your family,
just imagine,
if a person spends 1000 rupees a month
for himself, his wife, and his children,
and if they get any treatment,
why would he step back?
1000 rupees for the whole family,
including his wife, his children,
and his wife.
Add it and see,
we have good health insurance plans every month.
If you see,
it will increase every year.
But, you can spend 1000 rupees every month.
Take health insurance for yourself and your family.
Don't tell us about the problems outside.
We might not even save enough money.
We might get loans.
But, we don't live with loans.
We live with the next generation.
We don't take it to the next level.
If we don't take health insurance,
we might commit a big mistake.
So, please don't neglect it.
Take a good health insurance plan
for your family.
If you don't have the money to pay 1000 rupees a month,
if you don't have the money to pay 1000 rupees a month,
if you fill your details,
and give your wife, children,
and their details,
just imagine how much you will spend.
Just imagine how much you will spend a month.
Next, before your birthday comes,
try to take insurance.
Because, if it's your birthday,
your age will increase.
Now, check it.
Adjust it before your birthday.
Adjust it and try to take a good health insurance.
Finally, why should I change the insurance I took?
It was a good plan when I took it.
But, later on, I told you about the new features.
Optima, Reastore, Secure,
Neva Bhoopa, Care.
They started giving good features for less money.
So, I thought of shifting.
I should have shifted last year.
But, to make it portable,
from one insurance company to another,
to become portable,
I will be paying the premium in the next week.
I won't have to go now.
Minimum 45 days.
Some people say 30 days.
But, we should port it before 45 days.
I am telling you how to port in policy market.
If you go ahead to take policy,
you will see the premium calculator.
Click on Port Existing Policy.
If you go ahead,
it will ask for your old policy details.
If you update all the details,
you will take a new policy from the old policy.
The advantage of this is,
the waiting periods I had,
I will complete all the waiting periods.
All the benefits will come here.
So, people who are already taking health insurance,
don't take it as a new policy.
Keep it as it is.
If it ends after a while,
take a new policy from 2 months ago.
And port it.
So that the benefits you paid till now,
will shift to this.
All the waiting periods will cool off.
So, if you are taking this policy,
port option,
if you are already taking health insurance,
and if you are not,
click on the link and see how much you will get.
If possible, don't neglect it today.
If you don't take it today, you won't take it again.
Since you watched the video today,
take the initiative and take a good health insurance for yourself and your family.
Till now,
if you have found out any new information by watching the video,
and if you have found out anything new,
mention it in the comment section.
Tell us a few words
about the efforts we have made.
If you didn't like the video,
like it.
We have to understand how much knowledge
they will get if we share this with them.
Share this video with your friends and family.
I will come back with another interesting video.
Till then, take care.
Jai Hind!